Another way to measure turnover,
周转率的另一种衡量方式是
is called the factor rank autocorrelation.
因子排名自相关系数
The factor rank autocorrelation is close to one,
当股票的排名每天变化不大时
when the ranking of stocks doesn't change much from day to day.
因子排名自相关系数接近 1
To give you an illustration,
举个例子
let's imagine our universe consists of just two stocks, apple and alphabet.
假设股票池仅包含两支股票 Apple 和 Alphabet
If over several days,
如果在很多天
the rank of apple,
基于 alpha 信号的 Apple 排名
based on its alpha signal is always two,
始终为 2
and the rank of alphabet is always one,
Alphabet 的排名始终为 1
then the previous ranks of each stock are
那么每支股票之前的排名
perfectly correlated with the current day's ranks.
与当前的排名完全相关
In other words, the ranks are highly
换句话说 排名是高度相关的
correlated or the factor rank autocorrelation is close to one.
或者因子排名自相关系数接近 1
When the ranks of stocks don't change much from day to day,
当股票排名每天变化不大时
this also means that the weights of our theoretical portfolio don't change much either,
表明理论投资组合的权重也变化不大
which means less trading,
这就表明交易量更少
and therefore less turnover.
进而表明周转率更低
To calculate the factor rank autocorrelation for a single time period,
为了计算单个时段的因子排名自相关系数
we'll get the ranked alpha vector for the previous day,
我们需要获取前一天的已排名 alpha 向量
and also the ranked alpha vector for the current day.
以及当天的已排名 alpha 向量
Then we calculate the Spearman rank correlation
然后计算之前和当天的已排名 alpha 向量
between the prior days and current days ranked alpha vectors.
之间的斯皮尔曼排名相关系数
We can repeat this for multiple days and a time window,
我们可以针对时间窗口内的多个日期重复这一流程
so that we have a time series of factor rank autocorrelations.
获得因子排名自相关系数的时间序列
A high factor rank autocorrelation is a proxy to indicate that the turnover is lower.
很高的因子排名自相关系数表明周转率很低
A low, or even negative factor rank autocorrelation,
很低甚至为负的因子排名自相关系数
would then indicate high turnover.
表明周转率很高
Let's look at how we would use a turnover measure,
下面看看如何在知道其他评估指标的情况下
such as factor rank autocorrelation in the context of other evaluation metrics.
使用周转率衡量指标 例如因子排名自相关系数
If two alpha factors have similar sharpe ratios,
如果两个 alpha 因子具有相似的夏普比率
similar quintile performance, and similar factor returns,
相似的分位数业绩和相似的因子收益率
we'll always prefer the one with lower turnover.
我们将始终选择周转率更低的 alpha 因子
If an alpha factor has high sharpe ratio,
如果 alpha 因子的夏普比率很高
but very high turnover,
但是周转率非常高
we may need to consider whether the alpha factor would survive backtesting,
我们可能需要考虑 alpha 因子能否通过
paper trading, and real trading.
理论交易的回溯测试并在实际交易中取得成功
As a reminder of why lower turnover helps us,
解释下为何较低的周转率可以帮助我们
it makes it more possible for us to execute trades if
如果股票流动性高
the stocks are liquid and can reduce our transaction costs.
我们更有可能执行交易 并且能够降低交易成本
Managing turnover is a delicate balance.
周转率是比较难权衡的指标
On one hand, we want high turnover because that
一方面 我们希望周转率很高
means alpha factor is taking advantage of new information,
因为这意味着 alpha 因子在利用新的信息
and making more trades which likely implies higher breath.
并作出更多的交易 说明广度更高
However, on the other hand,
但是另一方面
trading costs money and
交易带来成本
excessive turnover could mean the alpha is simply capturing noise.
过高的周转率表明 alpha 只是捕获了噪点
Over time, the more you work in alpha research,
当你对 alpha 的研究越来越久后
the more you will develop intuition about this.
就会培养对周转率的敏感性
Evaluating alpha factors is both an art and a science.
评估 alpha 因子既是一门科学 又是一门艺术
Keep in mind that factor rank autocorrelation is different than rank IC.
注意 因子排名自相关系数与排名 IC 不同
Even though these metrics both use ranking and correlation,
虽然这两个指标都用到排名和相关性
rank IC is measuring whether an alpha factor is correlated with forward returns,
但是排名 IC 衡量的是 alpha 因子是否与远期收益率相关
while factor rank autocorrelation is measuring how
而因子排名自相关系数衡量的是
stable the ranked alpha vectors are from day to day.
已排名 alpha 向量每天的稳定性